Register of the John S. Applegarth Collection, 1964-1965
Hoover Institution Archives
John S. Applegarth Collection,
1964-1965
64011
Applegarth, John S., collector.
4 manuscript boxes, 3 envelopes, 1 phonotape (1.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Ephemeral publications, propaganda leaflets, newspaper clippings, photographs, placards, and a sound recording, relating to the riots in the Panama Canal Zone in January 1964 and to activities of political parties in Mexico, and Central and South America.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Scope and Content of Collection
Ephemeral publications, propaganda leaflets, newspaper clippings, photographs, placards, and a sound recording, relating to the riots in the Panama Canal Zone in January 1964 and to activities of political parties in Mexico, and Central and South America.
Access Points
Riots--Panama.; Latin America.; Latin America--Politics and government.; Panama.; Panama Canal.
Container List
- Panama and Canal Zone (Box 1)
  - Anti-Castro Propaganda, Spring 1965
  - Balboa High School and Canal Zone College
  - National Elections of 1964, posters and ephemera
  - News releases from Quarry Heights press office, January 1964
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - Panama Canal Information Office, Daily Digest, January 1964
    - Panama Canal Review, January 1964 and February and May 1965
    - La Estrella de Panama, January 1964
    - Star and Herald, January 1964 (Box 2)
    - The Panama American, January 1964
    - El Dia, January 1964
    - La Critica and La Hora, January 1964
    - El Panama America, January 1964
    - Spillway, January and February 1964
    - Clippings from Colombian newspapers, February - December1964
    - Clippings from countries other than Panama and Colombia
    - Clippings from Panamanian papers about U.S. relations with Panama, 1965
  - Pamphlets and other ephemeral material, March - July 1965
  - Panama Canal and Canal Zone Government
    - Information Office releases, March - July 1965
    - Office of Internal Security, political ephemera, and list of communists (Box 3)
  - Partido Democratica Cristiano, political ephemera
  - Posters and placards
    - Crisis of 1964
    - Rally at Parque Santa Ana, Panama City, May 5, 1965
    - Labor Day, May 1, 1965
  - Santo Domingo agitation, 1965
  - Sugar workers' march, April 1965
  - Television script for General Mabry's talk on the riots
  - U.S. Consulate, travel brochures, July 1965
  - U.S. Information Office, Bogota, Colombia, leaflet on Panama Canal crisis of 1964
  - U.S. Military Operations
- Colombia (Box 4)
  - Communist Party in Colombia
  - Communist activities against the Universidad del Valle and the U.S. Peace Corps, 1964
  - Newspaper clippings, 1964
  - Partido Social Democrati Cristiano, posters, 1964
  - Universidad Del Valle
- Costa Rica
  - Partido Alianza Popular Socialista, 1965
  - Partido Liberacion Nacional, 1965
  - Unificacion Nacional Party, 1965
- Dominican Republic, poster, 1965
- Guatemala, political ephemera and clippings, 1965
- Honduras
  - Political ephemera, 1965
  - Posters on Viet Nam war, 1965
- Mexico
  - Newspaper clippings from Voz Obrera (Trotskyite newspaper), 1965
  - P.A.N. and P.R.I., party posters, 1965
- Peru, oil industry, communist leaflets, 1965
- Peru, Ecuador, and Venequela, 1964